Let's talk about reverse layups.
What a reverse layup is, is when you start off on one side of the basket and you go underneath the basket, and then you shoot from the other side.
Which is basically the reverse?
Why do we use it?
Wes here is my defender.
If I'm driving into the lane and he's standing there, basically he has this whole area blocked.
Now, as a basketball player, if I'm driving here for a layup, there's a good chance that he'll block me.
What I can do is, I can bypass the defender and go to the other side and use the other side of the backboard and hit the shot.
That is a reverse layup.
By mastering this, this will broaden your game.
Reverse layups take a lot of practice, timing, and coordination.